In this video, we're going to cover the infrastructure map,
which tells us all the different component pieces that we're planning on as part
of phase one of Cerebro. You can find the,
ah, infrastructure map over here on the sidebar.
You can also access it from a mobile phone from the same website.
Infrastructure map shows us, ah,
all the different, ah, things that we have to pay for on a monthly
basis to be able to host this kind of technology.
So you'll see right here that if we look here at Railway,
it costs $20 a month. There's also a pro plan that's required for Superbase,
which is the database we choose. And then,
ah, GitHub has actually free plans,
so you don't have to do anything for that. There's going to be more
infrastructure needs, but we'll start there.
And I would say that this is probably 80 to 90% of the bill
anyway. The only other major thing to watch out for is if you need
any dynamic AI directly available.
Inside is Cerebro, and that's going to be, ah,
like paying for, ah, electricity. Just however many kilowatt hours you use in the
world of AI, we call it tokens. So let's take a look at the
map, and we'll see over here on the first part of it that each
of these cards represents a source system that we have to pull data in
from. As I told Michael today when we,
ah, spoke together, ah, and we settled on the idea that some things
are going to be pulled data in and others are going to be pushed,
and that we'll figure that out as we go. Ah,
Navisoft, if you were to click on this, it actually opens up a sidebar,
and you can see a lot of information about Navisoft,
how it works, the data availability, et cetera. And so this first version is
just kind of a way to be able to see where the data comes
from, but we'll have some more information over here as time goes on,
including, ah, stakeholders, who do you call when something breaks,
things of that nature. Thank All right. I'll pull the map over here so
you can take a look at the Data Demon. The Data Demon is a
back-end process only, and it runs in Railway.
Ah, I did a Railway video, so if you go watch that one,
you can kind of learn a little bit more about how that works. The
Data Demon is a program that runs in the background,
and it is, has one job, and that's to go grab all this data,
and then double-check it, and move it through the pipeline.
So, it is reaching out its arm,
grabbing someone's hand. Ah, after it authenticates,
and then it's doing some calculations, and it's moving it over into the warehouse,
which is stored in Supabase. Um,
the warehouse is going to have three different layers inside of it,
what's called a bronze layer, a silver layer,
and a gold, and I'll get into what those three things mean here in
just a second. But you can also click on it and learn a lot
about this as well, and of course, if you have any questions about how
infrastructure works, or you're just curious how,
all this fits together, you can always pull up a,
uh, uh, what is it, the Claude sidebar,
and just ask it, you know, plain English, explain to me why we would
do this, uh, things of that nature. Okay,
but let's get into what data movements are.
So first off, this is called a medallion architecture,
it's extremely common in both finance and also in healthcare,
but, uh, you'll also find it, um,
in any system that has to have canonical data,
uh, pulled in from one place and then stored for a warehouse use later.
The bronze layer basically means this,
um, give me a piece of data, like this,
this page right here, and just store it,
just store the picture of it, uh, don't put it into columns,
don't put it into rows, don't try to stick it in a,
a tabular format, don't make it a spreadsheet,
don't remove dollar signs, don't move negative signs,
you literally store it the exact same way that you received it from the
source system. There's a huge reason why you want to do this.
If you pull it once from the source system and you store it raw,
you never have to pull it again because you got a photocopy of what
it was. In the silver layer,
that's when we actually run a little bit of code to take that raw
data and then convert it into something that we can,
uh, use, such as taking,
uh, counting, uh, numbers, that come in that have parentheses around them,
removing the parentheses, and putting a negative sign in front.
That is called a transformation, and we can do that step during the silver
layer. So you have the bronze pulling in raw data.
Silver is where we take that data and we clean it up and normalize
it into something like, uh, is it words,
is it numbers, is it decimal places, and do all that kind of cleanup
stuff. There's another reason that we want to separate out into these different layers,
and that's because when there's a data error or a data issue,
we can basically isolate where that error came from.
Was it a transformation issue trying to remove parentheses,
or was it actually that the data just didn't load? Um,
and then lastly, we have what's called a gold layer, and that one is
business metrics and KPIs, and the gold layer is essentially where we
combine data across multiple sources together.
That's not always true. Uh, in some systems,
the gold layer is just one system, so that would,
that would mean that Navisoft alone could have its own bronze,
silver, and gold layer, but I'm going to kind of cross over in this
discussion and just simply say that sometimes the gold layer is where you combine
things as well, and that's a perfectly valid way to look at it.
So, to recap the goal there,
imagine for a moment that you had a HubSpot contact.
But you also had Navisoft current clients,
and you wanted to combine those into a singular view.
We also need a third table added in,
which is going to be a Normalized Customers table,
or a Leads table, or a Prospects table.
Something that is, has the sole job of linking the HubSpot
person over to the, uhm,
Navisoft person. That's one technique.
Another technique, sometimes people don't use, is where they pick one system to be
the canonical list. They say, this is the golden list,
and everybody will always be in this list,
and even if they're not in another system, they will always be in this
system. But that's the best way to do it. You always want to have
one system that has at least, you want to have at least one system
that has everybody. And we can choose whether that's Cerebro,
HubSpot, Navisoft, or, uhm,
a combination thereof. So that's That is how the Medallion architecture works,
bronze, silver, gold. And once you have gold,
that's when you can hook it up into live dashboards.
You can, uh, hook it up to alerting systems, you can hook it up
to an AI, you can hook it up to automated reports that go into
people's email, uh, you can hook it up to a mobile app,
you can hook it up to, uhm,
heck, you can hook it up to a speaker that you can talk to
on your desk and ask questions of. Uhm,
Thank you. All of that happens downriver of the Cerebro process itself.
So the Data Demon's job is to take all these things from this place
and then to put them over here in the Unified Warehouse. And that,
in a nutshell, is how the architecture works.
I'm sure that I'll be adding more onto this as we go.
So why build this in the first place? Why build the map?
Well, first off, I love when we can easily and quickly explain how something
works through, uh, you know, a diagram, but also because if we build this
out first and then have a discussion together about whether we like it or
dislike it, it allows us to perfect the chart that you see right in
front of you and get it just right with all the rules,
restrictions, governments, and regulation before we even have to write any code,
meaning that code doesn't have to be rewritten because it was mistake-prone.
So this is like, uh, the map, the treasure map for how we need
to get there, and AI can basically write code that matches the treasure map
and that allows us to finish things a lot faster as well.
If you have any other questions, let me know. Thank you very much.
Have a good night.